Guide to the Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Information Files, ca. 1890s-present AIS.Info.Files
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Information Files
ca. 1890s-present
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. Archives Service Center
AIS.Info.Files
40 Linear Feet
The Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Information Files contain ephemeral materials related to the political, social and economic history of Pittsburgh and other parts of southwestern Pennsylvania. These include brochures, fact sheets, small pamphlets and other informational publications on local organizations, religious institutions, parks, government departments/offices, etc. There is at least one folder in the Information File for each of the headings listed below. Items in the AIS Information Files are available for public use in the Archives Service Center Reading Room and may be photocopied upon request.
Previous Citation
Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) Information Files, [folder name], Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Acquisition Information
Created by the Archives Service Center staff since 1979.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Architecture; Women; Associations; Business and Industry; Churches and Synagogues; Education; Environment; Ethnic groups; Government; Health and medicine; Labor; Politics; Social action; Societies
- A
  - AMVETS; SEE American Veterans of World War II and Korea
  - A.R.C. House; SEE Alcoholic Recovery Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Abbott Family
  - Abortion Rights Coalition (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Academy of Science and Art (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Access Video of Western Pennsylvania, Inc.
  - Adath Jeshurun Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Addison H. Gibson Foundation
  - Advertising
  - Aero Club of Pittsburgh
  - African Americans
  - Agadis Achim Russian Hebrew Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Agudath Achim Congregation (Punxsutawney, Pa.)
  - Aiken, T. Negley
  - Air Force Association. Greater Pittsburgh Chapter
  - Alcoholic Information Center and Clinic (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Alcoholic Recovery Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Aliquippa (Pa.)
  - Aliquippa Jewish Community Center; SEE Jewish Community Center (Aliquippa, Pa.)
  - Aliquippa Steel Company
  - All Saints Polish National Catholic Church
  - Allderdice High School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Allegheny (Pa.)
  - Allegheny (Pa.)- Biography
  - Allegheny Academy (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Allegheny Arsenal (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Allegheny Cemetery (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Allegheny College (Meadville, Pa.)
  - Allegheny Council for Intergovernmental Action
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Maps
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Statistics, Vital
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Bureau of Bridges
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Department of Administration
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Department of Adult Services
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Department of Airport Area Development
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Department of Elections
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Department of Parks
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Department of Planning and Development
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Department of Works
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Government Study Commission
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Health Department
  - Allegheny County (Pa.)- Office of Economic Opportunity
  - Allegheny County Anti-Saloon League (Pa.)
  - Allegheny County Association of Township Supervisors (Pa.)
  - Allegheny County Bicentennial Commission (Pa.)
  - Allegheny County Board of Assistance
  - Allegheny County Board of Commissioners
  - Allegheny County Citizens Commission for Public Schools
  - Allegheny County Civic Sportsmen's Association
  - Allegheny County Council of Defense
  - Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights
  - Allegheny County Court; SEE Pennsylvania. County Court (Allegheny Court)
  - Allegheny County Courthouse and Jail (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Allegheny County Emergency Association
  - Allegheny County Federation of Women's Clubs
  - Allegheny County Free Fair
  - Allegheny County Industrial and Training School for Boys; SEE Thorn Hill School (Warrendale, Pa.)
  - Allegheny County Juvenile Court; SEE Pennsylvania. Court of Common Pleas (Allegheny County). Juvenile Section
  - Allegheny County Labor Council
  - Allegheny County League of Women Voters; SEE League of Women Voters (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Allegheny County Medical Society
  - Allegheny County Planning Commission
  - Allegheny County Transit and Traffic Commission
  - Allegheny County Workhouse (Pa.)
  - Allegheny General Hospital (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Allegheny High School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Allegheny Housing Rehabilitation Corp.
  - Allegheny Regional Planning Council
  - Allegheny Reservoir (Pa. and N.Y.)
  - Allegheny Trail Alliance
  - Allegheny Valley Association for Racial Equality
  - Allegheny Valley Service Bureau
  - Allentown (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Alliance for Consumer Protection (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Alliance for Progressive Action (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Alliance of Guardian Angels; SEE Guardian Angels (Organization)
  - Allied Boards of Trade of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Company. Pittsburgh Works.
  - Alternative Education Resource and Development Center
  - Amen Corner (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - American Association of Social Workers. Pittsburgh Chapter
  - American Association of University Women. Pittsburgh Branch
  - American Bridge Company
  - American Cancer Society. Allegheny County Unit
  - American Civil Liberties Union. Greater Pittsburgh Chapter
  - American Coordinating Committee on Corrosion
  - American Croatian Congress (1st,; 1943; Chicago, Ill.)
  - American Defenders of Bataan & Corregider Memorial Society
  - American Friends Service Committee. Pittsburgh Pretrial Justice Program
  - American Friends Service Committee. Pittsburgh Program Committee
  - American Institute of Architects. Pittsburgh Chapter
  - American Jewish Committee. Pittsburgh Chapter
  - American League Against War and Fascism. Pittsburgh Committee
  - American Marketing Association. Pittsburgh Chapter
  - American Red Cross. Pittsburgh Chapter
  - American Romanian Institute for Research
  - American Service Institute
  - American Slovak Day (Kennywood Park (Pa.))
  - American Standard, Inc.
  - American Veterans of World War II and Korea. Allegheny County Council
  - American Wind Symphony Orchestra
  - Americans for Democratic Action. Pittsburgh Chapter
  - Americus Republican Club (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Ancient Order of Hibernians
  - Animal Friends, Inc.
  - Another Side (Organization)
  - Anti-Semitism
  - Apartment Association of Metropolitan Pittsburgh
  - Arab Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Arena football- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Arlen Specter Center for Public Policy (Philadelphia, PA)
  - Arlington (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Armstrong and Shidle
  - Armstrong World Industries. Beaver Falls Plant
  - Art Society of Pittsburgh
  - Arts and Crafts Center of Pittsburgh
  - Asbury Heights (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Asbury Methodist Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Asian Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Associated Charities of Pittsburgh
  - Associated Contractors Agency, Inc.
  - Association for the Study of Afro-American Life and History. Pittsburgh Branch
  - Association of Community Councils (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Assumption Church (Leechburg, Pa.)
  - Ateleta Beneficial Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Audubon Society of Western Pennsylvania
  - Avery College
  - Avery Memorial African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- B
  - Bailey Family
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America. Local 44 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Baldwin (Pa.)
  - Baldwin Community United Methodist Church (Pa.)
  - Baldwin Township (Pa.); SEE Baldwin (Pa.)
  - Bank Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bank of Pittsburgh
  - Beaver (Pa.)
  - Beaver Falls (Pa.)
  - Beechview (Pa.) Community Council
  - Belle Vernon (Pa.)
  - Bellefield Area Citizens Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bellefield Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Beltzhoover (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bennett, James I., 1822-
  - Bessemer (Pa.)
  - Beth Hamedrash Hagodol- Beth Jacob Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Beth Israel Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Beth Israel Congregation (Washington, Pa.)
  - Beth Israel Synagogue (Indiana, Pa.)
  - Beth Shalom Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.); SEE Congregation Beth Shalom (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bethel African Methodist Episcopal Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bethel Presbyterian Church (Washington County, Pa.)
  - Bethesda United Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.). Community Center
  - Beulah Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Beverly Heights United Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bickur Cholim Convalescent and Nursing Home (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bidwell Cultural and Training Center (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Big Brothers of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - BirthPlace; SEE Western Pennsylvania Hospital. BirthPlace
  - Bissell Family
  - Bituminous Coal Operators' Association
  - Black Construction Coalition (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Black Crafts Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Black Family
  - Blacks; SEE African Americans
  - Blair Family
  - Blaw-Knox Co.
  - Bloomfield (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bloomfield-Garfield Corp.
  - B'nai B'rith. District 3
  - B'nai B'rith. McKeesport Lodge No. 573 (McKeesport, Pa.)
  - B'nai B'rith. Pittsburgh Lodge 44 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - B'nai Emunoh Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - B'nai Israel Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - B'nai Zion Congregation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Board of Trade of Pittsburgh (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Bounties, Military- Pennsylvania- Maps
  - Boy Scouts of America. Allegheny Council
  - Boy Scouts of America. East Boroughs Council (Wilkinsburg, Pa.)
  - Boy Scouts of America. Yohogania Area Council
  - Boyle, Tony; SEE Boyle, William Anthony, 1904-1985
  - Boyle, William Anthony, 1904-1985
  - Boys Club of Western Pennsylvania
  - Bradley Family
  - Brashear Association
  - Brewing industry- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Bridges- Pennsylvania- Allegheny County
  - Bridges- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - British Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Brockway Glass Company
  - Brother's Brother Foundation (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Brown Family
  - Brown, William H.
  - Brownsville (Pa.)
  - Brunot, Felix R. (Felix Reville), 1820-1898
  - Buhl Planetarium and Institute of Popular Science (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Building Laws- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Building Rehabilitation Investment Co., Inc.
  - Bulgarian Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Bureau of Community Councils (Pittsburgh, Pa.); SEE Health and Welfare Federation of Allegheny County. Bureau of Community Councils)
  - Burgwin Family
  - Business and Job Development Corporation
  - Business and Professional Women's Club of Pittsburgh, Pa.
  - Business enterprises- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh- History
  - Byers Family
  - Byzantine Catholic Day (Kennywood Park (Pa.))
  - Byzantine Ruthenian Metropolitan Province of Munhall (Pa.); SEE Catholic Church. Byzantine Ruthenian Metropolitan Province of Munhall (Pa.)
  - Byzantine Slavonic Rite Catholic Diocese of Pittsburgh (Pa.); SEE Catholic Church. Exarchate of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
- C
  - Calvary Episcopal Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Calvary United Methodist Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Carlow College (Oakland, Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Carnegie Family
  - Carnegie Institute, Dedication Programs, 1907
  - Carnegie Steel Company
  - Carnegie Steel Company; SEE ALSO Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation; SEE ALSO Carnegie Steel Company
  - Carnegie-Illinois Steel Corporation. Irvin Works
  - Carpatho-Rusyn Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Carrick (Pa.)
  - Castle Shannon (Pa.)
  - Catholic Boy Welfare Bureau (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Catholic Church. Byzantine Ruthenian Metropolitan Province of Munhall (Pa.)
  - Catholic Church. Diocese of Greensburg (Pa.)
  - Catholic Church. Diocese of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Catholic Church. Exarchate of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Catholic Diocese of Pittsburgh (Pa.); SEE Catholic Church. Diocese of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Catholic Knights of St. George (U.S.)
  - Catholic Library Association. Western Pennsylvania Unit
  - Catholic Youth Association (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Catholic Youth Association (Allegheny County, Pa.); SEE ALSO Catholic Youth Bureau (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Catholic Youth Bureau (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Catholic Youth Bureau (Allegheny County, Pa.); SEE ALSO Catholic Youth Association (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Celtic Americans- Pennsylvania; SEE Celts- Pennsylvania
  - Celts- Pennsylvania
  - Cenacle Retreat House (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Center for Victims of Violent Crime (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Central Catholic High School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Central High School (Pittsburgh, Pa.); SEE Pittsburgh Central High School (Pa.)
  - Chalfant Family
  - Chamber of Commerce of Pittsburgh
  - Charleroi (Pa.)
  - Chatham University
  - Chatham Village (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Chautauqua Society of Greater Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Chess Family
  - Children's Aid Society of Western Pennsylvania
  - Children's Home of Pittsburgh
  - Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh
  - Chinese American Republican Club of Greater Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Chinese Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Christ the Divine Teacher Roman Catholic Church (Beaver Falls, Pa.)
  - Christian Associates of Southwest Pennsylvania
  - Church, Samuel Harden
  - Church buildings- Pennsylvania
  - Church of Saints Peter and Paul (Beaver, Pa.)
  - Church of St. Peter (Brownsville, Pa.)
  - Church of St. Therese the Little Flower (Munhall, Pa.)
  - Church of the Ascension (Ingram, Pa.)
  - Church of the Ascension (Pittsburgh, Pa.: Episcopal)
  - Church of the Epiphany (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Churches- Pennsylvania; SEE Church buildings- Pennsylvania
  - Citizen's Political Union of Pittsburgh and Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Citizens Against Inadequate Resources (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Citizens Against Slum Housing (Pittsburgh, Pa.)--Dorothy M. Richardson article
  - Citizens to End White Racism (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Citizens' Committee for the Welfare Bond Issue (Pa.)
  - City Firemen's Protective Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - City of Pittsburgh; SEE Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - City of Pittsburgh Fire Fighters; SEE Pittsburgh (Pa.). Fire Department
  - Civic Club of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Civic Light Opera Association of Greater Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Civic Unity Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Civic Air Patrol. Allegheny County Squadron; SEE United States. Civic Air Patrol. Allegheny County Squadron
  - Civil Service Reform Association of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Clairton (Pa.)
  - Clapp Family
  - Clark Family
  - Clean Community Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Club Cultural Espanol de Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Cneseth Israel Congregation; SEE Congregation Cneseth Israel (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Coal Mines and Mining- Pennsylvania
  - Coalition '71 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Coalition '72 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Coll, E. B.
  - Colonial Land Company
  - Columbia Gas System, Inc.
  - Committee for Conservative Action (Havertown, Pa.)
  - Committee for the Abolition of Corporal Punishment in the Public Schools (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Committee for the Equal Rights Amendment (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Committee of Fifty on Advisability of a Community Fund for Pittsburgh (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Community Action Pittsburgh, Inc.
  - Community Action Regional Training (Pa.)
  - Community Chest of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Community Fund Council (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Community Hearing Council of Greater Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Community Human Services Corp. (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Community Partners Corp. (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Concerned Citizens of Homewood-Brushton (Pa.)
  - Concordia Club (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Conemaugh Valley Conservancy
  - Conference for Action Against Poverty (Pittsburgh, Pa.: Nov. 5-6, 1966)
  - Conference for Victory and a Free World (Pittsburgh, Pa.: Nov. 23-24, 1942)
  - Conference on Discipline and Violence in School and Society (Pittsburgh, Pa.: Nov. 1-2. 1968)
  - Conference on Handicapped Individuals, Inc. Region V
  - Congregation Beth Shalom (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Congregation Cneseth Israel (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Congregation Machsikei Hadas (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Congregation O'Have Israel (Brownsville, Pa.)
  - Congregation of the Sisters of the Holy Ghost; SEE Sisters of the Holy Ghost
  - Congregation Poale Zedeck (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Congregation Shaare Zedek, Anshe Poland (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Congregation Tree of Life (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Congregation Tree of Life-Sfard (McKeesport, Pa.)
  - Congress of Women's Clubs of Western Pennsylvania
  - Consolidated Natural Gas Company
  - Consolidation Coal Company
  - Construction Advancement Program of Western Pennsylvania
  - Consumer Cooperative of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Converse, Edmund C.
  - Cooperative Welfare Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Copperweld Corporation
  - Corey Family
  - Corpus Christi Roman Catholic Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Council of Jewish Women (U.S.). Greater Pittsburgh Section
  - Council of Jewish Women (U.S.). Greater Pittsburgh Section; SEE ALSO National Council of Jewish Women. Pittsburgh Section
  - Council of Medical Social Service Boards (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Council of Three Rivers American Indian Center
  - Court Records
  - Courthouse Gallery/Forum (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Croatia
  - Croatian Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Croatian Day (Kennywood Park (Pa.))
  - Croatian Fraternal Union of America
  - Crohn's and Colitis Foundation of America, Western Pennsylvania /West Virginia Chapter, 1999-2001
  - Cvetic, Matthew, 1909-
  - Czech Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Czecho-Slovak Pact (Pittsburgh Agreement)(Pittsburgh, Pa.: May 30, 1918)
- D
  - Daft Family
  - Danko Family
  - Darrah, Dorothy C.
  - Daughters of Erin. Court #9 (Pittsburgh, Pa.); SEE Knights of Equity. Court #9 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Dayton Charge Methodist Episcopal Church (Dayton, Pa.)
  - De Paul Institute (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Deutschen Ordens der Harugari (Etna, Pa.)
  - Dialogue, Inc. (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Dickson Family
  - Dilworth Family
  - Dinkey Family
  - Diocese of Greensburg (Roman Catholic); SEE Catholic Church. Diocese of Greensburg (Pa.)
  - Divine Redeemer Roman Catholic Church (Ambridge, Pa.)
  - Donation and Depreciation Lands- Pennsylvania- Maps; SEE Bounties, Military- Pennsylvania- Maps
  - Dormont Presbyterian Church (Dormont, Pa.)
  - Dornic, Ivan
  - Drug Addicts of the Greater Pittsburgh Area (Pa.)
  - DuBois (Pa.)- Maps
  - Duquesne Garden (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Duquesne High School (Duquesne, Pa.)
  - Duquesne University. Tamburitzans
- E
  - East Indian Americans- Pennsylvania
  - East Liberty (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - East Liberty Community Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - East Liberty Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - East Liberty Trade Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Easter Seal Society for Crippled Children and Adults of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Edgewood (Allegheny County, Pa.)
  - Educational Institute of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - El Salvador Mobilization Committee (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Election Districts- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Electrification- Pennsylvania- Pittsburgh
  - Elfinwild United Presbyterian Church (Glenshaw, Pa.)
  - Elliott Company
  - Elliott Family
  - Emergency Committee of Concerned Citizens (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Emma Kaufmann Camp
  - Emmanuel Church (Allegheny, Pa.)
  - Engineers' Society of Western Pennsylvania
  - English Americans; SEE British Americans
  - Environment: Pittsburgh
  - Epiphany Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.); SEE Church of the Epiphany (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Episcopal Church Home (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Episcopal Church. Diocese of Pittsburgh
  - Erste Warshover Unterstitzungs Verein
  - Ethnic Groups- Pennsylvania
  - Everson Family
  - Executive Women's Council of Greater Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Explorers Club of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Eye and Ear Institute of Pittsburgh (Pa.)
- F
  - F. L. Ober & Bro. Brewing Co.
  - Family Service Association of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Family Society of Allegheny County (Pa.)
  - Farland, Alfred A.
  - Fayette County (Pa.)
  - Federated Russian Orthodox Clubs. Central Pennsylvania District
  - Federated Russian Orthodox Clubs. Pittsburgh District
  - Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of Pittsburgh
  - Federation of War Veterans Societies of Allegheny County, Inc.
  - Feminist Network Project
  - Fieser Family
  - Fifth Avenue High School (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Filipino Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Film Forum of Greater Pittsburgh (Pa.)
  - Finleyville (Pa.)
  - First Catholic Slovak Union of America
  - First Christian Church (Braddock, Pa.)
  - First Church of Christ, Scientist (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - First Congregational Church (Etna, Pa.)
  - First English Evangelical Lutheran Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - First Presbyterian Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - First Unitarian Church of Pittsburgh
  - First United Methodist Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - First United Presbyterian Church (Braddock, Pa.)
  - Fischer, Mary Ann
  - Florence Crittenton Home (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Foerster Family
  - Forbes Field (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Forbes Road (Pa.)
  - Foreign Policy Association. Pittsburgh Branch
  - Forests and Forestry
  - Forever Action Together, Inc.
  - Fort Pitt Block House and Edith Darlington Ammon Memorial Garden
  - Fort Pitt Brewing Co.
  - Fort Pitt Museum (Pa.)
  - Foster, Stephen Collins
  - Foundation for the Study of Cycles (U.S.)
  - Four Mile United Presbyterian Church (Beaver, Pa.)
  - Fourteenth Ward Citizens' Council (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Fourth Ward Soldiers and Sailors Welfare Association (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Free and Accepted Masons; SEE Freemasons
  - Freedom House Enterprises
  - Freemasons. Bellefield Lodge, No. 680 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Freemasons. Lodge No. 45 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Frick, Henry Clay, 1849-1919
  - Frick Community Health Center; SEE Henry Clay Frick Community Hospital (Mount Pleasant, Pa.)
  - Frick Family
  - Frick Hospital; SEE Henry Clay Frick Community Hospital (Mount Pleasant, Pa.)
  - Frick Training School for Teachers (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Friendship (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Fuel-Gas and Electric Engineering Co.
- G
  - G-20 Summit Protest Events
  - GASP (Group Against Smog and Pollution) (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Gaelic Arts Society (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Gambling on River Boats
  - Garfield (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Garland, Robert
  - Garrison, Abraham
  - Gay and Lesbian Community Center of Pittsburgh
  - Gayley Family
  - Geography Club of Western Pennsylvania
  - George Junior Republic Association
  - George Washington Carver Week
  - German Americans- Pennsylvania
  - German United Evangelical Congregation of Birmingham (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Gibson Foundation; SEE Addison H. Gibson Foundation
  - Gimbel Brothers. Pittsburgh Store
  - Gimbel's Department Store (Pittsburgh, Pa.); SEE Gimbel Brothers. Pittsburgh Store
  - Glass Manufacture- Pennsylvania
  - Glen Hazel Area Citizens Union (Pa.)
  - Golub, Solomon
  - Good Shepherd Lutheran Church (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
  - Goodwill Industries
  - Government Study Commission, Allegheny County (Pa.); SEE Allegheny County (Pa.). Government Study Commission
  - Government Study Commission, City of Pittsburgh (Pa.); SEE Pittsburgh (Pa.). Government Study Commission
  - Graff Family
  - Grand Army of the Republic. Department of Pennsylvania
  - Greater Pittsburgh Chamber of Commerce; SEE Chamber of Commerce of Pittsburgh
  - Greater Pittsburgh Commission for Women (Pa.)
  - Greater Pittsburgh Council on Adult Education
  - Greater Pittsburgh Guild for the Blind
  - Greater Pittsburgh International Airport
  - Greater Pittsburgh International Airport. Ribbon Cutting Ceremony (September 30, 1992)
  - Greater Pittsburgh Slovak Heritage "76"
  - Greek American Progressive Association
  - Greek Americans- Pennsylvania
  - Greek Catholic Union of the U.S.A.